hey
I'm Kedesha and here's what I'm thinking about Model Context Protocol
MCP MCP
the MCP has been everywhere and it's not going anywhere
instead it's going to be more integrated into our environments
our daily lives as developers
as humans using AI right
so what is MCP and what's the purpose of it
so MCP stands for Model Context Protocol
and it is an open protocol that standardizes how LLM applications
talk to your external data sources
so let's say you're in Claude
and let's say you want Claude to be able to help you
to automate your email
now just by itself
if I say hey Claude
hey Claude
if I say what's on my schedule today
Claude won't know because it doesn't have context or information
about what's on my schedule
I don't have access to your calendar or schedule information
so I can't see what you have going on today
but because of MCP I can connect my calendar to Claud
now I'm not going to be doing this
because I don't have a demo calendar here
but think about the possibilities if
my calendar is connected to Claude
I can come in here and say
hey Claude what's on my schedule today right
you get a list of what's on your schedule today
you can say hey Claude
can you add so and so to my schedule
can you add X meeting to my schedule
think about the possibilities right
so what's the purpose of MCP
the purpose of MCP
is to provide additional context to your LLM applications
and your LLM in general
because models are only as good as the context they have
or the context that you provide them with
if LMS don't have the ability to connect to other apps and tools
it's not as useful as it can possibly be
and I have my notes here uh
because I've been working on a blog post that's gonna come
out next week with the same information right
so with MP servers
is essentially what LLMs have to connect to the outside world
so you know
how you can install a plugin or a Chrome extension on your browser
to be able to connect with other things
and do additional things on your browser
that's the same thing but for Llms so we have Chrome extensions
large language models have MCP servers
did that make sense
I hope it did so a little bit about the architecture of MCP servers
right so the MCP is based on a client server architecture
and this should sound very similar to you if you're a developer
because that's rest and that's also the Language Server Protocol
LSP which was established back in 2016 by Microsoft
that details how IDEs interacted with programming languages right
it standardized how IDEs interacted with programming languages
basically and so there are three core tenants of MCP
there's the host there's the server and there's the client
so I'm gonna read my notebook
so MCP Host is a LLM app that wants to access data through MCP
so for example think of Claude here
this is an MCP host and also VS code
that's right behind Claude on my desktop right now
is also an MCP host right
an MCP server is a lightweight program
that each expose specific capabilities through MCP
so an MCP server could be the Github MCP server
could be the Figma MCP server
it could be the Canva MCP server
right and cloud
they're called connectors
but these are all CP servers right
so you have Gmail Canva
Asana Atlassian
you have in video to turn your ideas into video
you have Versal CP Server
there are so many MCP server
now if you're a developer
and you want to explore developer specific MCP server
you can do that in VS code
so if I go here and go to my extensions
and sir if you put at MCP
if you click on this browse MCP server
just pop this here
you will see a list of MCP servers that you can install in VS code
and the great thing about this is it's just one click install
so if I click install context 7
and Context 7 is a way for large language models to get up to date
information about up to date version
specific documentation
and code examples from any library or framework
great so open VS code and now context 7 is installed in VS code
just like that right
so one click install so how can I interact with contact 7
well if I open up copilot here and I click on this tools button
you're going to see all the tools that you have available
so there are built in tools
but right here you can see there's MC
there's a Github MCP server that I have connected
and there's the Context 7 MCP server that I have connected right
and so
that's pretty much how simple it is to connect MCP server in VS code
as a developer and of course
you can use these MCP servers in other applications as well
not just VS code right
that's the magic of MCP servers
it gives your LMS
additional context and access to your external data sources
that's all I want you to think about when you think about MCP servers
right and so
MCP client
is what maintains that 1 to 1 connection with host applications
so Claude here serves as both an MCP host and an MCP client
from my understanding and so does VS code
VS code serve as an MCP host and an MCP client
as an MCP host VS
code provides the environment and the runtime for MCP clients
to connect to MCP servers
and as an MCP client when VS code connects to MCP servers
it instantiates an MCP client object to manage that connection alright
so that's what I'm thinking about today
I'm thinking about MCP let me know what questions you have about MCP's
let me know what MCP's you're playing around with
I'm very keen to play with the NHN MCP and also the Appify MCP
cause I'm looking into some automation stuff
but let me know what questions you have
have you tried MCP what MCP are you using
do you know what MCP is are you excited about this as I am
until next time when I tell you what I'm thinking about
I'm Kedesha bye